Goudy Type Collection
Goudy Type Collection
Undated
Goudy, Frederic W. (Frederic William), 1865-1947.
approximately 12 linear ft.
Two cabinets of original type, by noted American type designer Frederic Goudy.
4840068
Biographical History
Frederic W. Goudy (1865-1947) was an American printer and type designer of more than 120 fonts, among them Copperplate Gothic, Kennerley, and Goudy Old Style. Frederic's wife Bertha M. Goudy worked closely with him and was a noted graphic designer in her own right. Both Frederic and Bertha were self-taught. Goudy had a long-standing relationship with Syracuse University (SU); he was awarded the distinguished service medal by SU's Newhouse School of Journalism in 1936, received an honorary doctorate from SU in 1939, and was appointed a lecturer at the School of Journalism in 1940. Dates given are the dates the typeface was designed, but may not be the actual date this type was cast.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Goudy Type Collection consists of two large cabinets of lead type, designed by noted American type designer Frederic W. Goudy. Important fonts in the collection include Deepdene, Sherman, and Goudy Newstyle.
Arrangement of the Collection
In original cabinets, in original order.
Related Material
See also the
Frederic W. Goudy Collection
,
David M. Norton Collection relating to Frederic Goudy
, and
Charles Pont Collection relating to Frederic Goudy
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Goudy, Frederic W. (Frederic William), 1865-1947.; Graphic design (Typography) -- United States.; Letterpress printing -- United States.; Printing -- United States -- History.; Type specimens (documents); Typefaces (Type forms); Printers.; Type designers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Viewing of this collection must be scheduled in advance. The cabinet may only be opened for viewing when the Lemke Seminar Room is available and with an SCRC curator present.
Acquisition Information
Originally in the posssession of Syracuse University's S. I. Newhouse School of Journalism, the collection was at some point transferred to the School of Visual and Performing Arts and then, in 2008, to.
Inventory
- Goudy type
  Drawer 1 is empty.
  - Tory 24 pt., 1935 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 2)
  - Tory 18 pt., 1935 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 3)
  - Sherman 14 pt., 1912; 10 drawers (Cabinet 2, Drawer 4-13)
  - Truesdell 16 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 14)
  - Truesdell 18 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 14)
  - Goudy Newstyle 18 pt., 1921 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 15)
  - Trajan Title 12 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 16)
  - Trajan Title 18 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 16)
  - Trajan Title 24 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 1, Drawer 16)
  - Trajan Title Ornate 30 pt., 1930? (Cabinet 1, Drawer 17)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 16 pt., 1932; 2 drawers (Cabinet 2, Drawer 1-2)
  - Goudy Village Italic 14 pt., 1934 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 3)
  - Goudy Village Italic 16 pt., 1934 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 4)
  - Tory 14 pt., 1935 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 5)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 14 pt., 1932 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 6)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 16 pt., 1932 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 7)
  - Medieval 14 pt, 1930 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 8)
  - Medieval 16 pt., 1930; 2 drawers (Cabinet 2, Drawer 9-10)
  - Medieval 24 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 11)
  - Medieval 30 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 12)
  - Medieval 36 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 13)
  - Medieval 48 pt., 1930 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 14)
  - Deepdene 18 pt., 1927 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 15)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 Small Caps 12 pt., 1932 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 16)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 Small Caps 14 pt., 1932 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 16)
  - Goudy Village No. 2 Small Caps 16 pt., 1932 (Cabinet 2, Drawer 16)